## **Arpit Vaish**

Email: - arpitvaish@hotmail.com

Mobile no.: - +91- 9582914277

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with **7.5 years of experience** developing and designing robust applications in **Java technologies (Primarily Back End developer) with some exposure in Front-End Technologies as well** like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery into various domains like IOT, Industrial, Engineering and services, E-commerce, Health and Insurance. Supportive and enthusiastic team player with experience in leading team.

I have good background in algorithms with many certification by University of San Diego (CourseEra) in Algorithms, String Algorithms, Graph Algorithms.

My github url : <a href="https://github.com/arpitvaish">https://github.com/arpitvaish</a>

### SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

- Programming Languages: Java/J2EE, Micro-Services, Apache Camel, Design Patterns
- o Databases: MySQL, DB2, Oracle
- Framework: Spring, Spring Boot, HazelCast, Maven, Gradle
- Application Servers: Apache Tomcat, JBoss Fuse, JBoss WildFly
- o Cloud Services: AWS, Docker, Docker-compose
- Coding environment (Operating Systems): Windows, Linux, Unix
- Messaging framework: Active MQ
- Web Development: REST, HTML (basics), CSS (basics), JavaScript (basics)
- o Agile Methodology, Sonar Qube, Git Lab

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

PRINICPLE ENGINEER (JULY 2019 - PRESENT)

STANDARD CHARETERED BANK

WORKING AS BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER IN HYPERLEDGER

### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (APRIL 2017 - JULY 2019)

SIEMENS TECHNOLOGY AND SERVICES PVT. LTD.

Worked is software developer for the product MindSphere which is an IOT application built on Java and Spring Boot. I developed several modules in Java like reporting system and remote connectivity application.

For reporting module, I created a back-end application to feed enormous data to the front end application that helped to display analysis of various remote devices.

For remote connectivity application, was involved in backend coding of device connectivity and high-speed file transfers.

Technologies/methodology used are: Micro-services, Java, SpringBoot, AWS, ActiveMQ, Tomcat, Data Structures & Algorithm, Agile, SonarQube, GIT, Docker, PostGreSQL, REST.

### SOFTWARE CONSULTANT (OCTOBER 2015 - APRIL 2017)

### CAPGEMINI TECHNOLOGY SERVICES INDIA LTD

Worked as middle ware developer for GE client on Java/J2EE, SOA, OSGi, Blueprint, Apache Camel, Active MQ, JBOSS FUSE, PL/SQL, Spring, Hibernate, JAX-B, XML, XSLT. The project is to get live data regarding various attributes of locomotives (trains and trucks) like health of engine, temperature of engine etc. from satellites through which the engineering team gets into action. I was involved as a core module developer and designing the application to handle 1,000,000 messages in 1 minute.

Technologies/methodology used are: Micro-services, Java, Spring Apache Camel, Apache Karaf, ActiveMQ, Tomcat, Data Structures & Algorithm, Agile, SonarQube, GIT, Oracle, AWS, REST.

# FUNCTIONAL SYSTEMS ANALYST (SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - SEPTEMBER 2013 – OCTOBER 2015)

### **AON CORPORATION**

Here I was one of the first members of the team called Digital Solutions and Innovation. My major responsibilities were web development and lead a team of 10 members.

I worked on web development for health and insurance domain. Work included develop web application on many technologies like java, php, html, JavaScript, jQuery and other web technologies, design strategies, team management and client interaction.

Technologies/methodology used are: Java, Tomcat, Hibernate, Data Structures & Algorithm, GIT, MySQL.

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER (JULY 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2012)

### INTERSCAPE TECHNOLOGIES INC.

This is a start-up company that deals with performance analysis of Storage servers and arrays. Here I worked on creating a tool that would automate report generation in PDFs and Excel regarding performance and health of Storage servers and arrays around the globe. The technologies I used were PHP and MySQL.

Technologies/methodology used are PHP, MySQL.

### **EDUCATION / CERTIFICATION**

- MBA / PGDM (Executive, Business Analytics 1 Year course)
  - o University: Institute of Management Technology (Ghaziabad)
  - o Year: 2018
  - o Score/Marks: 75%
  - Dissertation: Sales Backorder prediction using Machine Learning and R Language. In this I
    created a software using R Language to predict sale back order for HomeDepot. The data was
    taken from Kaggle and utilized HighCharts (JS) for displaying graphs.
- Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering (4 year course)
  - o University: Rajasthan Technical University
  - Year: 2011
  - Score/Marks: 71.66%
- Oracle certified Java Associate (Java 7)

### AWARDS AND ACHIVEMENT

- Received exemplary performance award for continuous delivery of quality deliverables.
- Received platinum award for best team of the year.
- Lead the college basketball team.

### PERSONAL DETAILS

• Name: - Arpit Vaish

• Father's Name: - Chiranjeev Lal Gupta

• **D.O.B:**- June 07<sup>th</sup>, 1989

• Gender: - Male

• Address: - Electronic city, Bangalore, India

• Current City: - Bangalore, India